NIKOL PROKOPOVA

Web Developer

London, UK n.prokopova96@gmail.com 07549151895 GitHub LinkedIn Portfolio

SUMMARY

I embarked on an unconventional journey that began with studying biotechnology and delving into the intricacies of genetics, where I contributed to the development of a custom DNA sequencing instrument. However, my exposure to programming ignited a realisation within methat my true passion lies in the realm of technology and computers.

Despite my fascination with genetics, I found my calling in web and app development, leveraging my innate way of thinking and affinity for computing. Over the past two years, I've honed my skills in Typescript and React, alongside mastering HTML and Vanilla CSS along with various libraries.

SKILLS

React (Next.js, Gatsby.js), TypeScript, Node.js, AWS, Tailwind CSS, HTML, CSS (FlexBox, CSS Grid), Vanilla JS, Styled Components, Git, GitHub, BitBucket, Gitlab, StoryBook, MaterialUI, Jira, Jenkins, RESTful APIs, Nunjucks, jQuery, SCSS, SQL, Contentful CMS, AWS, Email development, Continuous Integration

EXPERIENCE

Oxford Nanopore Technologies - Frontend Developer

JAN 2024 - PRESENT

Tech stack: React, TypeScript, Electron, Node.js, Tailwind CSS, Nextflow, AWS, Preact, Nextflow

- Developing a desktop app used for bioinformatics analyses at a DNA Sequencing company
- User interface development via React, TypeScript and Tailwind CSS
- Back end development with Node.is
- Implementation of external libraries for bioinformatics visualisation
- Working on compatibility with MacOs, Windows and Linux
- Cloud development via AWS
- Preact and Signals implementation

AKQA, London - Web Developer

NOV 2022 - JANUARY 2024

Tech stack: Vanilla JS, React, TypeScript, HTML, SCSS, jQuery, Nunjucks, Contentful CMS, SQL, Git, BitBucket, JIRA, Jenkins, Node.js, SQL, AWS, Continuous Integration, Mailchimp, Email Development

- Worked at a design agency supporting the development of the front end on various projects
- Led the development, support and deployment of the company website
- Led the development of a React <u>project</u> based on this year's creative requirements to create an animated, interactive web-app
- Supported the marketing team to provide timely and stable solutions to urgent requests
- Managed a MySQL database
- Worked in SCRUM
- Worked on the implementation of Google Analytics 4
- Used Git and ButBucket for version control
- Wrote JIRA tickets

Codeum Ltd, London - Junior Web Developer

FEB 2022 - NOV 2022

Tech stack: React, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, NextJS, StoryBook, MaterialUI

- Worked at a web agency, creating custom React components to construct UI libraries in StoryBook
- Developed Components for a Ul library with Storybook and Material Ul Implemented code into NextJS projects
- Created reusable React components according to specifications
- Met with the development team to discuss user interface ideas and applications
- Used Git and GitHub for version control
- Used Jira for project management Worked in SCRUM (biweekly sprints)
- Communicated to team members and management

DNA Electronics. London - Associate Scientist

SEP 2019 - NOV 2021

Tech skills: Python, Jira, Jenkins, Data analysis and visualisation

- Worked towards the development of a first of its kind medical device utilising Next Generation DNA Sequencing technology at a dynamic inter-disciplinary start-up
- Designed and conducted experiments for biochemical optimisation of semiconductor sequencing technology
- Led work packages that resulted in significant improvements in sequencing performance
- Modified Python scripts to run experimental machinery
- Led issue-tracking meetings and used Jira as platform and was a laboratory leader
- Troubleshot and communicated with cross-functional team members

Nanyang Technological University, Singapore - Research Assistant

SEP 2017 - JUN 2018

- Molecular cloning, PCR, Bacterial culture, identification and characterisation
- Used advanced software to design gene constructs
- Constructed bacterial plasmids and performed genetic knock-off mutation in *E.coli* bacteria

EDUCATION

University of Surrey, London - Biotechnology JUN 2019 First class honours

CERTIFICATES

FreeCodeCamp Responsive Web design
FreeCodeCamp JavaScript Algorithms
Codecademy React Course
FreeCodeCamp Front End Development Libraries